Hello everyone and welcome to English Pot.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and
today we're going to play a game.
That's right, today we're going
to describe someone's face.
So we're going to try to
guess who that person is.
Okay, so there are lots
of really great words
to describe people's
faces in this lesson.
Let's take a listen to
today's dialogue and we'll
be back in a moment to
talk about what's going on.
Let's play a game.
Okay, how about Scrabble?
No, no, a friend of mine
taught me this really fun game.
I'm going to describe someone's
face and you guess who it is.
Okay.
Let's see, he has a Roman nose,
bushy eyebrows and dimples.
Our cousin Pete, my turn.
She has a pointy nose, sunken
eyes, and a mole on her chin.
It rose.
That mole is so huge.
Okay, my turn.
He has a crooked nose and full lips.
He has quite a few
freckles and an oval face.
Oh, he's also bald.
Your future husband.
Not funny.
All right, we're back.
So now let's take a look
at five key words that we
have to describe someone's
face on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So we've got a couple words for noses here.
They're adjectives to describe noses.
The first one that we heard is Roman nose.
Okay, so if someone has a Roman
nose, does that mean they're from Rome?
No, not quite.
Well, Rome, as we know, is a city in
Italy, but it's also an adjective here.
Roman means that the
nose is straight on top.
It's like a triangle.
Okay, but it's kind of long.
You have kind of a
long, straight nose, right?
That's right, a very long, straight nose.
Okay, so we have Roman nose,
somebody that has a long, straight nose.
Now, what about a pointy nose?
A pointy nose means that
the tip of the nose is pointy.
So maybe it goes up
a little bit, it's down
and then up, but usually that
there's a point on the tip of the nose.
Or sometimes the nose is very thin, right?
It's very, it's not very
wide, so it looks very pointy.
That's right, so it kind of gets
very narrow at the end of it.
That's right.
Okay, and now maybe
you broke your nose once,
or you had an accident, and
some people have a crooked nose.
Yeah, a lot of very
famous football players
have crooked noses,
because you know you get
hit in the face with the football, and
then your nose always has a bump.
Right.
Well, look, something is
crooked if it's not straight.
So crooked is the opposite of a
Roman nose, or a straight nose.
That's right.
So maybe you see
boxers also, I think, have
crooked nose most of them, or
hockey players and stuff like that.
Yeah, they take a lot of hits to the face.
Okay, so now moving
on, we've described rope
noses in many ways, and
you can say long nose,
short nose, or whatever, but
this is another way of doing it.
And what about eyebrows?
Okay, eyebrows are those
lines of hair above your eyes.
And some people have really thick eyebrows,
some people have very thin eyebrows, but if
someone has thick eyebrows, lots
of hair, we call them bushy eyebrows.
Okay, so if you have
bushy eyebrows, it means
that you have a lot of hair on, as you
said, your eyebrows, or over your eye, okay?
And now this is a
really, I think, kind of a
nice feature that some people have
on their cheeks, we have dimples.
I love dimples, not many
people have them, but
these are two little dots, little
indentations that appear when a person smiles.
That's right.
So maybe you've seen
this, or maybe you have
this, or a friend has
this, somebody smiles.
And on their cheeks, towards the middle
of the cheek, they have little holes that
form that look like, I don't know, like
somebody kind of pinched it with a needle.
Yeah, like it goes in,
it goes down a little
bit for some reason,
it goes like, yeah,
they're being pinched inside their cheek.
That's right.
Those are called dimples.
Dimples.
Okay, so a lot of great stuff there in the
first part, let's review what we've heard.
Let's go back to the dialogue,
and we'll be back in a bit.
Let's play a game.
Okay.
How about Scrabble?
No, no, a friend of mine
taught me this really fun game.
I'm going to describe someone's
face, and you guess who it is.
Okay.
Let's see.
He has a Roman nose,
bushy eyebrows, and dimples.
Our cousin Pete, my turn.
She has a pointy nose, sunken
eyes, and a mole on her chin.
It rose.
That mole is so huge.
Okay, my turn.
He has a crooked nose and full lips.
He has quite a few
freckles, and an oval face.
Oh, he's also bald.
Your future husband.
Not funny.
All right, we're back.
So now we're going to take a look at
even more words on how to describe a face.
So now let's take a look at
language takeaway part two.
Language takeaway.
Okay, so the first word
has to do with the eyes.
We just talked about the
eyebrows, those are above your eyes.
Well, what happens if your eyes
are very, very deep in your face?
Okay.
We heard that in the
dialogue, because we
heard that in the dialogue
described as sunken eyes.
So sunken means very far
back or very deep in something.
That's right.
Think about a sunken ship.
It's under the water, under the ocean.
So someone with sunken
eyes probably has dark
rings under their eyes because
their eyes are so deep in their head.
That's right.
Now, I guess the opposite.
Maybe you've seen
people that have eyes that
are almost like
popping out a little bit.
Right.
His eyes pop out.
That means they come out of
the face, they're closer to the skin.
That's right.
Okay.
And now this is something
that many people
have and even some models have
become famous because of this.
Many times called a beauty
mark, we're talking about moles.
She Crawford is probably
the model you're talking about.
She had a very famous mole.
A mole is basically a spot on
your skin that's very, very dark.
So sometimes there's hair on it.
Sometimes it's texture
is different, but it's
a big, it can be small, but it's a
change of texture on your skin.
That's right.
So usually it's like a
little brown ball if it's big.
And sometimes they
just look like little
spots on your skin,
little dark brown spots.
That's right.
But they're not the same as
something else we heard in today's dog.
So we'll wait for that.
But a mole usually
comes a little bit off the
skin and it's usually
bigger than other dots.
That's right.
And I think what you're
talking about is freckles.
That's right.
Freckles.
A lot of people have
these when they're children.
They come on your nose
and your cheeks and even
your arms and they're
smooth with your skin.
They don't come off
your skin, they're not puffy.
That's right.
So I think many of you, maybe if you have
lighter skin, may have freckles and that's
usually just little spots but of
just different color on your skin.
So usually people that have maybe
red hair, you know, they have freckles.
Like maybe from the Harry Potter movie, the
Harry Potter's best friend, I think Ron.
You can see he has freckles.
That's right.
On his skin, he has lots of little dots
because he has very pale skin and red hair.
So these are called freckles.
That's right.
Okay.
And now when we
talked about lips, a nice
way of describing lips,
you can say big lips.
But that just means
that they're big, right?
But what about if that
person has full lips?
Full lips is a great way
to describe big lips.
We would say someone like
Angelina Jolie has very full lips.
That's right.
It means that they're not thin,
but they've got a lot of puff to them.
They have a lot of texture.
As you said, Angelina Jolie is probably
the best example of someone with full lips.
And now what about bald?
Someone who's bald.
Who's a good example for this?
Okay.
So this next where we've got is bald.
Who's a famous bald person?
Maybe you've heard of Kobe Bryant.
The basketball player.
That's right.
Now he's not completely bald.
He actually shaves his head,
but anyone who shaves their head
also has no hair on their head is
considered to be a bald person.
All right.
So bald means no hair on their head.
Right.
Now sometimes naturally people become bald.
Hair falls off as the years go by and
they know more hair grows on their head.
So they're bald.
That's right.
So this happens to a lot
of people, especially men.
They lose their hair.
Some people have a little bit of hair.
Some people lose all of their hair.
But when you lose hair on
your head, it's called going bald.
That's right.
Okay.
So now we have a lot of words
in how we can describe people.
And so why don't we go back
and listen to the dialogue again.
And we've got to talk a little bit more.
Let's play a game.
Okay.
How about Scrabble?
No, no.
A friend of mine taught
me this really fun game.
I'm going to describe someone's
face and you guess who it is.
Okay.
Let's see.
He has a Roman nose,
bushy eyebrows, and dimples.
Our cousin Pete, my turn.
She has a pointy nose, sunken
eyes, and a mole on her chin.
It rose.
That mole is so huge.
Okay, my turn.
He has a crooked nose and full lips.
He has quite a few
freckles and an oval face.
Oh, he's also bald.
Your future husband.
Not funny.
So we've talked a
lot about the different
parts of the face, but we have
not talked about one important part.
That's the bottom of a person's face along
that bone there, that's what we're called.
That's called the chin.
Okay.
So we could say some people have
very, very prominent or big chins, right?
Like for example, Jay Leno.
Oh, yeah.
His chin is so big.
It's almost a joke among
people that he has this big chin.
That's right.
So he has a long chin.
Now other people may
have a very square chin, right?
So it's almost like it looks like a
square on the bottom of their face.
Otherwise you could have a round chin.
That's right.
And the opposite part of
the face is also very important.
We call it not the top of your
head, but we call it your forehead.
Your forehead.
Now some people have
a very big forehead, right?
Because maybe their hair
grows a little bit further back.
And other people have a smaller forehead
so you almost can't even really see.
Or sometimes they just
hide it with their hair.
That's right.
And now actually talking
about chins, there's
another type of chin
that's also very popular.
John Travolta's chin.
That is, he has a dimple in his chin.
That's right.
I remember we were
talking about dimples of
those little holes where you
can have them in other places.
And the chin is one of them.
That's right.
So I think that's called a butt
chin if I'm not mistaken, right?
And then even as I've
heard it before, I'm not
sure how to answer
you, but yeah, all right.
But maybe this is a
good time to encourage
you all to tell us about your facial
features or to describe someone for us.
Use some of the vocabulary
that you heard today.
That's right.
Or maybe you even just
want to describe someone
famous and we can guess
what you're talking about.
Good challenge.
So we will see you on our
website, www.EnglishPod.com.
All right.
We'll see you guys there.
Bye.
[MUSIC PLAYING]